



+1 480.703.1830

linkedin.com/in/diane-serpa-53112b6

https://dianead70.myportfolio.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Professional graphic designer and art director with 19 years of experience in identity design, marketing design production, concept development, and creative strategy. Successful track record in the marketing, printing and mailing services, as well as supply management.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### DESIGNER AND ART DIRECTOR

6/2009-present ~ FREELANCE ~ GREYCATDOT **DIGITAL DESIGN** 

Paperclip Publishing, Mary L. Holden - Editor, Bestway Global, Republic Services, New Direction Coaching, Artsmith Kids' Art Bronx, Bat Conservation International, GLSEN Phoenix, ASU

### GRAPHIC DESIGNER

11/2011-2/2013 ~ ALLEGRA MARKETING AND PRINT

- » Conceptualize + design graphics for social media platforms + direct marketing materials
- » Variable data + pre-press production and QA
- » Design large format print materials

#### • SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER

2/2000-5/2009 ~ INSTITUTE FOR SUPPLY MANAGEMENT

- » Conceptualize + design multiple international publications
- » Conceptualize + design a wide variety of collateral materials
- » Brand management
- » Pre-press production
- » Photo retouching + Illustration

# **EDUCATION**

- 1991–Colorado Institute of Art ~ Associates Degree in Visual Communication
- 1989–Mesa Community College ~ Associates Degree in Fine Arts, Honors

## **KEY SKILLS**

Able to expertly use industry-leading applications, such as Adobe Creative Suite, to effectively conceptualize and create campaigns for digital and print media. Special skills are variable data using XMPie and ePub digital publishing. Strong skills through collaboration, time management, problem solving, emotional intelligence, and teamwork. Comfortable with communications with international and local clients and stakeholders.

### **TOOLS**

InDesign	Illustrator	Photoshop
MS Word/Excel	Dreamweaver	HTML/CSS

# **PROJECTS**

- Logos/Identity
- Advertising
- Targeted Direct Marketing
- Publications
- Web/Mobile Graphics
- Website Design
- InfoGraphics
- Typography
- Event Marketing
- Variable Data
- XMPie
- Email Layout
- Beginner UI/UX

## PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

- Phoenix InDesign Users Group, member: 2009-present; volunteer Board Marketing Director: 2015-present
- AIGA-Arizona, current member
- Phoenix Design Week, volunteer: 2009, 2010, 2014, 2016

